SARA KEVORKIAN FRONT END DEVELOPER

SUMMARY

I am a Seattle-based front end developer that has delivered for a variety of industries including non-profit, real estate, big oil, and airlines. I am primarily a front end developer with some back end development experience. My background in biotech taught me the importance of flexibility and the mindset to break concepts down into testable pieces. I am an analytical thinker and love to ask questions, while keeping a collaborative, positive mindset. In my 3+ years of experience I have learned new technologies quickly to meet project needs.

EXPERIENCE

Sr Consultant - Front End Developer, Seattle

AVANADE, Dec. 2019 - Current

Ownership of front end features while creating responsive, engaging web experiences

Build reusable, easily maintainable components or design patterns with accessibility best practices

Provide guidance on technical feasibility for new designs

Work closely with design and client teams to clarify requirements

Collaborate with backend developers on data structures and transfer

Research approaches to challenging features and create proofs of concept

Present project work or new technologies at internal meetings Mentor two junior front end developers in their careers

Notable Projects:

April 2020 - Current

Using React/Redux, delivered a public-facing nonprofit site to connect donors and volunteers during COVID-19 in 1 month

Extended into enhancement/maintenance phase

Implemented social media tracking pixels, Google Tag Manager, and Google Analytics

July 2019 - April 2020

Delivered a new internal employee Sharepoint productivity hub for a large corporation

Lead FED within a primarily offshore team

Launched pilot stage in 3 months and was extended into second phase of project

While on this project received Avanade North America's November "Recognizing Excellence" award and Seattle team's "Studio Champ" for January 2020

Consultant - Front End Developer, Seattle

Dec. 2018 - Current

Notable Projects:

May 2019 - June 2019

Built the UI of a workflow app for developers to bring new apps to the cloud using React

Lead FED on a team with two junior onshore FEDs

June 2018 - Feb 2019

Delivered a simpler and more intuitive version of a US airline's internal policy search tool using Sitecore and Coveo

Lead FED on a team with one junior onshore FED

Sr Analyst - Front End Developer, Seattle

Aug. 2017 - Nov. 2018

Notable Projects:

April 2018 - June 2018

As the Lead FED, integrated the newest version of Coveo search into an existing Angular/Sitecore intranet site

Guided a junior developer to finish remaining bugs within a set bucket of hours

While on this project awarded Seattle team's "Studio Champ" for May 2018

Aug 2017 - March 2018

Worked with the existing development team to solve UI bugs for a Coveo-driven Sitecore corporate real estate search site

Extended as the sole front end developer - responsible for performance enhancement and new feature requests

Improved performance of business critical property search page by 50-75%

Web Development Immersive, Seattle

GENERAL ASSEMBLY, Mar. 2017 - June 2017

Accelerated project oriented learning - 50+ hours per week over 3 months. Worked individually and as a team to develop full-stack web applications.

Clinical Research Associate - Molecular Analysis / QC Lead, Seattle

HEMATOLOGICS INC., Nov. 2014 - Feb. 2017

Worked within an interdisciplinary team performing clinical DNA testing; prepared molecular lab for CAP audit

Molecular Technologist II/Quality Assistant, Seattle

GENELEX CORPORATION, Sept. 2013 - Nov. 2014

Performed high throughput clinical DNA testing; managed purchasing and quality databases.

Sept. 2012 - Sept. 2013

Molecular Technologist I, Seattle Molecular Technician, Seattle

Sept. 2011 - Sept. 2012

EDUCATION

TOOLS

GENERAL ASSEMBLY Web Development Immersive 2017

ARTI ITTES

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, Node.js, Express.js, React, Angular.js, Bootstrap, SQL, MongoDB, Web APIs, Git/Github, Materialize, Coveo, Sitecore, SASS, LESS, Gulp, Grunt, Akumina, Sharepoint Troubleshooting, Teamwork, Communication, Flexibility, Positivity, Organization, Self-Reliance

SKILLS